Finding Aid for Mark Wayland Tenny visual materials, 1895 and 1897
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Mark Wayland Tenny visual materials 1895 and 1897
Tenny, Mark Wayland.
1 volume and 1 oversize folder
92972 Aa 1; UAm
Holly, Michigan resident. Sketchbook of Jacksonville, Florida views, including buildings and ships; watercolor of the University of Michigan Library; and a drawing of the library clock tower at the University of Michigan.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was donated by Mary and Emery George (donor no. 6798 ).
Periodic additions to the records are not expected.
The collection is open to research.
Mark Wayland Tenny was an civil engineering graduate of the University of Michigan, class of 1895. As a hobby, he painted and drew the sights he saw on his travels.
The Tenny collection consists of one sketchbook containing depictions of the buildings, houses, and ships harbored at Jacksonville, Florida. There are also two drawings of University of Michigan views, the library and the clock tower of the library.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Florida.; Ships--Florida.; University of Michigan. Library.
Genre Terms:
Drawings.; Paintings.
- Sketchbook, 1897, 12 x 17 cm
  - Three Friends [ship], 1/22/1897 Jacksonville, Fla., 1.
  - Dr. Daniels old place near Panama Park, Fla., Jan 31, 1897, 2.
  - Jacksonville, Fla., 1/24/1897, 3.; house, upside down in sketchbook
  - Rock Road [curve], Jacksonville, Fla., 1/27/1897, 4.
  - Rock Road [fork], Jacksonville, Fla., 1/28/1897, 5.
  - On Dr. Daniels Old Place near Panama Park, Fla., Jan 31, 1897, 6.
  - Dauntless [ship], Jacksonville, Fla. 2/21/1897, 7.
  - Cypress, 2/21/1897 [vertical], 8.
  - Convict Camp out Main Street Jacksonville, Fla., 2/28/1897, 9.
  - Rock Road [house with paling fence] Jacksonville, Fla., 2/28/1897, 10.
  - U.S. Steamer "Vesuvius", Jacksonville, Fla., 2/28/1897, 11.
  - U.S. Revenue Cutter "Boutwell" Jacksonville, Fla., 2/28/1897, 12.
  - Out South Jacksonville Road, 3/7/1897, 13.
    (Five houses, three marked as follows: 1. To Rent; 2. Room for Six/10 x 16; 3. Dickerson (on porch)/ 16 x 16/Dry Goods, Groceries, Notions, Hay and Grain)
  - Out South Jacksonville Road [small church] illegible, 3/7/1897, 14.
  - South Jacksonville Road [cabin with ladder at chimney] 3/7/1897, 15.
  - Phelps Place, South Jacksonville Fla., 3/14/1897, 16.
  - Cypress/Phelps Place, S. Jacksonville, Fla., 3/14/1897 [vertical], 17.
  - Spanish Bayonet, 3/28/1897 [and] Cabbage Palmetta, 4/31/1897 [vertical], 18.
  - Live Oak, Phelps Place, S. Jacksonville, Fla., 4/11/1897 [vertical], 19.
  - One of Many, 4/4/1897 [cabin with wire fence], 20.
  - [Large church], S. Jacksonville, Fla., 4/4/1897, 21.
  - [Landscape with fences, shrine, cemetery (?)] S. Jacksonville Road Fla., 4/11/1897, 22.
- Other drawings
  - [University of Michigan Library], 3/14/1895, water color, 26 x 39 cm. on sheet 34 x 47 cm. (Folder 1)
  - [Clock tower of University of Michigan Library] undated, drawing, 38 x 24 cm. on sheet 47 x 35 cm. (Folder 1)